#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lawrence009 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

**PMP** 

Process Improvement SharePoint

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Chinese (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Pattern Discovery in Data Mining
The Data Scientist's Toolbox
Getting and Cleaning Data
Project Management Professional
Exploratory Data Analysis

# Lawrence Chen

Husband of Cancer Survivor | Data Scientist | Tableau Jedi Orange County, California Area

## Summary

Combining 20 years of experience in scientific research and program management, I help Experian solve its most challenging problems today with customer and market intelligence. Which sector is growing? How do we help businesses reach consumers, reduce risks and be more profitable?

For more information feel free to reach out to me at lawrence.chen@experian.com.

# Experience

Experian

15 years 1 month

Sr. Data Scientist, Credit Services February 2015 - Present (5 years 2 months)

Costa Mesa, California

Key industries: banks, credit unions, alternative lending, and fintech

Environment: RStudio, Python, SNL Financial, CapitalIQ, Oracle BI, MS SQL, Salesforce.com (SOQL/SOSL), AWS, GitHub, Alteryx, QlikView and Tableau

Program Manager

April 2007 - January 2015 (7 years 10 months)

Key programs and initiatives:

Sales Analytics (January 2012 - March 2015)

Finance Transformation (January 2010 - May 2011)

Cross-sell and Sales Enablement (April 2007 - March 2014)

#### **Environments:**

MS SQL Server Analysis Services (MS SQL, SSIS, SSAS), Hyperion Essbase, Oracle MDM, Salesforce.com connector, SOAP, Access, QlikView and Tableau

Siebel, Oracle, DB2, MS SQL, Access, Crystal Reports, Windward AutoTag, and SharePoint Reporting Service

IT Service and Relationship Manager March 2005 - November 2008 (3 years 9 months) Orange County, California Area

Major areas of focus:

IT Business Relationship (January 2007 - November 2008) E-Commerce Quality Assurance (March 2005 - March 2007)

Environment: Solaris, Red Hat, WebLogic, DB2, LoadRunner and Java

Oakwood Worldwide
Business Analyst/Consultant
January 2005 - March 2005 (3 months)

#### Accruent

Quality Assurance Director October 2003 - January 2005 (1 year 4 months)

Environment: Solaris, Red Hat, Windows, WebSphere, WebLogic, Oracle, MS SQL, DB2, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Business Objects, LoadRunner, Java and Visual Basic

Artemis International Solutions Corp.

Quality Assurance and Configuration Management Consultant
March 2003 - September 2003 (7 months)

TheBrain Technologies

Quality Assurance Director

March 2000 - January 2003 (2 years 11 months)

Founded in 1998, TheBrain Technologies is a software company specializes in mind mapping software. It's flagship product, PersonalBrain, has been popular in mind mapping circles, and runs on multiple operating systems. Its other major product, BrainEKP, received an award from the James Burke institute in 2008. Its other two products include BrainSDK and BrainEKP Connectors.

Cedars-Sinai Sr. Resarch Associate January 1997 - March 2000 (3 years 3 months) Greater Los Angeles Area Alpha Therapeutic Corp. Sr. Research Scientist October 1996 - January 1997 (4 months) City of Industry, California

NeXstar Pharmaceuticals, Inc.
Research Associate
October 1991 - October 1996 (5 years 1 month)
San Dimas, CA

# Education

University of California, Los Angeles
Postdoctoral Candidate, Bioinformatics and Computational
Biology · (1999 - 2001)

The University of Texas at Dallas - School of Management MBA, Project Management · (2004 - 2007)

California State Polytechnic University-Pomona
Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Biotechnology · (1989 - 1992)